■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
《开心汉堡店》第五季第三集
翻译：小布拿拿      Tiogy      红豆包      milkon
翻译&校对&总监：Iz
"老鼠认识你"除虫害公司
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
你们不用这罐子吧
I hope you didn't need this jar.
我们要用它装东西
We're getting into canning.
你们要装什么
What are you gonna can?
屁
Farts.
你需要的时候  往往没有
When you need one, you don't have one.
而有了一个之后  又需要更多
And when you have one, you need more!
用完后记得洗一下哦
Wash it when you're done!
等等  如果我们将屁冷冻起来
Wait. If we freeze the fart,
它就能永久保存了
it'll last forever!
等外星人出现时
It'll be all that's left of the human race
屁
它将成为人类唯一留下来的东西
when the aliens show up.
外星人  我们用屁对付你
Aliens! We farted on you!
我们到地下冷冻室去看看
Hey, let's go down and see
能不能造出屁粒子来吧
if we can make the walk-in cold enough to make fartcicles.
猜猜谁刚去医生那儿
Guess who just went to the doctor
做了五年一次的身体检查
for his five-year checkup?
柯尔斯蒂・艾利[美国女演员]
Kirstie Alley.
是我  三年来第一次裸体那么长时间
Me. Longest I've been naked in three years.
医生怎么说
Well, what'd he say?
都是老生常谈  你知道的
Doctor stuff. You know,
"你的胆固醇超标了"
"Your cholesterol is off the charts."
"你必须改变饮食习惯
"You absolutely must change your eating habits,
否则你会死的"  总之
or you will die." Anyway,
麻烦先给我来份芝士汉堡和薯条
one cheeseburger and fries, please.
也许你真的该上点心
Maybe you should be a little concerned, right?
你几乎每天一个汉堡
You eat a burger pretty much every day.
-这对你可没好处  -是啊
- That-that can't be good for you. - Yeah.
没错  但你们不也是每天都吃汉堡吗
Right. Don't you eat your burgers every day?
并不是每天
Not every day.
是啊  我们都点菜单上没有的菜
Yeah. We order off-menu.
这是我们的乐趣所在  对吧
It's how we have fun, right?
杀了我吧
Kill me.
真不错
That's nice.
总之  麻烦给我来份芝士汉堡和薯条
Anyway, cheeseburger and fries, please.
你确定要无视医生的嘱咐吗  泰迪
You sure you want to ignore your doctor, Teddy?
我并没有无视他
I'm not ignoring him.
我只是不听他的
I'm just not listening to him.
开心汉堡店
Bob's Burgers.
今日推荐汉堡
潜意识汉堡  5.95美元
我是泰迪的医生
This is Teddy's doctor.
我们来看一看泰迪的心脏吧
Let's take a look at Teddy's heart, shall we?
好吧
Okay.
好奇怪
That's strange.
好痒
Oh, hey... hey, that tickles!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
看看
Look at that.
恶心
Sick!
我能把它带去展示说明课吗
Can I bring that to show-and-tell?!
看到这个心脏有多不健康了吗
See how disgustingly unhealthy it is?
你每卖给他一个汉堡
And it gets bigger and bigger
他的心脏就会长大一点
with every burger you serve him.
医生  别再往他心脏塞汉堡了
Doctor, stop shoving burgers into his heart!
不是我塞的  鲍勃  是你
Oh, but I'm not, Bob. You are.
继续  鲍勃
Keep 'em coming, Bob.
天哪  不要
Oh, God, no!
继续塞
Keep 'em coming...
-不要  -继续塞
- No! - Keep 'em coming!
要爆炸了  要爆炸了
It's gonna pop! It's gonna blow!
对不起  泰迪
I'm sorry, Teddy!
什么  怎么了
What? What happened?
怎么了
What-what happened?
我在害泰迪
I'm killing Teddy.
什么  你要害泰迪
What? You're gonna kill Teddy?
好吧  汽车油加满了  很好
All right, car's gassed up. That's good.
看来我只能在家教孩子了  因为...
Guess I could home-school the kids 'cause...
-不是  琳  汉堡在害他  -什么
- No, Lin, the burgers are killing him. - What?
我每天都卖汉堡给他吃
The ones I give him every day.
明白了
Oh. Gotcha.
天  琳达  你这是设置了自动反馈吗
Good God, Linda. You had all that ready?
咋了  我只是想附和下你嘛  晚安
What? I'm just being supportive. Good night.
调低温度还真是管用
Lowering the temperature a few degrees really works.
我该穿高筒袜的
I should have worn my higher socks.
就是你们说的裤子
You guys call them pants.
它冻住了吗
Is it frozen?
抱歉  各位  没有屁粒子
Sorry, kids, no fartsicles.
真是失望至极
Just disappoint-sicles.
这次的实验是失败了
Well, this experiment was a bust.
蠢冰块
Stupid patch of ice!
抱歉  你并不蠢
Sorry, you're not stupid.
你只是很滑
You're just slippery.
等等
Hold on.
这蠢冰块也许是天才呢
This stupid patch of ice might actually be a genius.
到明天  这就会从垃圾场变成溜冰场了
And tomorrow, the walk-in goes from stinky to rinky.
做素食汉堡感觉好奇怪
Feels weird cooking a veggie burger.
而且  他会知道这不是正常汉堡的
Plus, he's gonna know it's not a hamburger.
不不  你不管给泰迪上什么他都会吃的
Nah, nah, Teddy'll eat whatever you put in front of him.
还记得他吃发票那次吗
Remember when he ate that receipt?
但愿你是对的
Well, I hope you're right.
这味道真奇特
This tastes kind of funny.
没必要去看它  吃就好了
You don't need to look at it. Just eat it.
口感像是汉堡  但称不上好
It tastes burger-ish, but not good.
你是故意做成这种口味的吗
Is that what you were going for?
这是  素食汉堡
It's a... veggie burger.
什么  素食汉堡
It's a what? A veggie burger?!
听着
Listen...
你为什么要这样
Why would you do that?
为什么
Why?
-泰迪  -这味道已经挥之不去了
- Teddy.. - Now I can't get the taste out of my mouth.
我不能昧着良心
Look, I can't in good conscience
每天卖你一个汉堡
serve you a burger every day.
我怎么没见你往莫特嘴里塞素食汉堡
I don't see you shoving a veggie burger down Mort's throat,
他不也每天吃汉堡么
and he eats a burger every day.
话不能这么说  我经常喝汤
That's not true. I often get the soup.
什么  你喝汤
What? You do? Soup?
别激动  泰迪
Take it easy, Teddy.
等等  泰迪  你每天都吃一个汉堡么
Wait, Teddy, you eat a burger every day?
-当然了  -那可真糟
- Of course I do! - That's messed up.
你也吃了不少汉堡  邮递员麦克
You eat a lot of burgers, Mike, the mailman.
是的  但我每天走九英里
Yeah, but I walk nine miles a day.
看看我的小腿
Look at my calves.
等等  别看我的小腿
Wait. Don't look at my calves.
并没那么出众
They're not that impressive.
这样吧  泰迪
Okay, here's the deal, Teddy.
我可以给你做汤或沙拉
I'll-I'll make you soup or salad,
但我不会再卖给你汉堡了
but I don't think I can serve you my burgers anymore.
你要断我粮  鲍鲍
You cutting me off, Bobby?
我想是的
I guess I am.
你要断我粮
You're cutting me off?!
这是在开混帐玩笑吗
Is this some kind of sick joke?!
我想这是为你好
I think it's for your own good.
你一边呆着去  莫特
You stay the hell out of this, Mort!
鲍勃  如果不让我吃汉堡
Bob, if you take your burgers from me,
别怪我杀了你和你那大嘴巴老婆
I will murder you and your mouthy wife.
什么
What?
对不起
I'm sorry!
我不知道自己在说什么
I don't know what I'm saying.
我要杀了你  给我汉堡
I'll kill you! Give me a burger!
泰迪
Teddy!
冷静
Calm... down.
你才冷静
You calm down!
天哪
Oh, my God.
我会换个新的
I will replace that.
我不想活了
I don't want to be alive.
I don't want to be alive!
他还算应对得不错
He's handling this well.
火  着火了  着火了
Fire! There's a fire. Fire!
不  琳  是闹钟
No, Lin, it's the alarm clock.
什么  关了它啊
What? Snooze it.
按钮坏了  你知道的
Oh, you know the buttons don't work.
我得拔电源才行
I have to unplug it.
谁去拔一下闹钟的电源
Someone unplug the alarm clock!
多谢
Thank you.
你这么早干嘛去
Where are you going so early?
我答应泰迪要和他一起去跑步
I told Teddy I'd go jogging with him.
他想证明给我看他很健康
He wants to prove to me that he's healthy enough
可以吃我们的汉堡
to be un-cut-off from our burgers.
不想跑步就别跑啦
Why are you running if you don't want to?
告诉老师你有坐骨神经痛就好了
Just tell your teacher you have sciatica.
你能这么帮你最好的朋友真让人感动
I think it's sweet you're helping your best friend.
泰迪不是我最好的朋友
Teddy's not my best friend.
泰迪认为你是他最好的朋友
Teddy thinks you're best friends.
-是吗  -当然
- He does? - Sure
等等  那谁是你最好的朋友
Wait. Who's your best friend then?
也许是瓦特・拉索
Probably Walter Russo.
瓦特・拉索
Walter Russo?
你最后一次和瓦特・拉索说话是什么时候
When was the last time you talked to Walter Russo?
不知道  六年前吧
I don't know, like, six years ago.
鲍勃  你每天都见泰迪
Bob, you see Teddy every day.
没错  但泰迪不是我最好的朋友  琳
Yeah, but Teddy's not my best friend, Lin.
他是我最好的顾客
He's my best customer.
这之间有很大差别
There's a big difference.
我也很珍惜我们之间
And I really value that 30 inches
那30英尺的距离
of Formica that's between us.
你是在暗指你的小弟弟么  别吹牛了
Are you talking about your dingdong, Daddy? Brag.
好了  得去陪我最好的顾客跑步了
Yeah, well, off to take my best customer jogging
以免他心脏爆炸
so his heart doesn't explode.
好吧  跑开心
All right, have fun.
你们俩都在老妈床上吗
Are you all in bed with Mom?
是啊
Yeah.
我来啦  我来啦
Coming up, coming up.
我的小海豹们
Oh, our little seal platform.
什么玩意儿
What is that?
我定的闹钟  我们走
My alarm clock. Got to go.
我们得去看一下  没什么
We gotta go check on... nothing!
对哦  可能那啥好了
Oh, yeah, maybe the nothing's ready!
简直  棒呆了
It's... perfect.
看我腿抬得多高
Look how high my knees are!
我的身体棒棒哒
I'm in great shape.
吃个汉堡没问题吧
Great enough for one burger?
不可以啊  泰迪
I don't think so, Teddy.
要报警吗
Should we call the cops?
这是小混混们在打晨架吗
Some kind of early morning gang brawl?
等等  我看他们不像是在真打
Wait... I-I think they're fake fighting.
麻烦问一下  出什么事儿了
Excuse me. What-what's going on over there?
我们管这叫特技训练营
It's called stuntman boot camp.
我现在身体非常好
I'm in the best shape of my life.
你是特技演员吗
You're a stuntman?
不  我只是像他们那样训练
No. I just train like one.
你也应该来看看
You should check it out.
手榴弹
Grenade!
又一发
And another grenade!
不得不说  感觉很酷啊
Got to admit, that looks kind of cool.
有点酷
Sort of cool.
那人看起来不怎么酷
Well, that guy doesn't look cool.
好  "手榴弹"场景排练的非常好
All right, great "Grenadies," Everybody.
别忘了报名参加周末两天的
Now, don't forget to sign up for the intensive,
丛林强化训练
weekend-long, stuntman boot camp in the woods.
在那儿你将学会这个
Where you might learn how to do this.
-演示一下  -现在这是一座
- Go ahead. - Now this is actually
起火的十层高大楼  我身上也着火了
a ten-story burning building, and I'm on fire.
着火了
On fire!
-着火了  着火了  -好大的火啊
- I'm on fire! I'm on fire! - So much fire!
像是浑身着火一样跳到地上打滚
Falling and rolling like you're on fire
这燃烧的卡路里和跑步一样多
burns as many calories as running, people.
这就是为什么  真要比的话
That is why, pound for pound,
特技演员才是这世上最出色的运动员
stuntmen are the greatest athletes in the world.
击掌
Up top!
我还以为是高尔夫选手呢
I thought it was golfers.
不是吗
It's not golfers?
冷冻效果太赞了
Holy frozen nips!
看看这地方
Look at this place!
好滑啊
It's so slippery!
是啊  我们都觉得很赞
Yeah, we like it.
还行吧
It's all right, I guess.
那  你们要在这下面干嘛呢
So, what do you do down here?
我们尝试了好多种游戏
Well, we've experimented with lots of stuff.
玩过冰壶
We tried curling.
躺在冰上
We tried lying on the ice.
透心凉啊
That was refreshing.
有人喜欢  有人不太感冒
Some of us didn't like it as much as others,
但我们尊重每个人的意见
but we respect their opinions.
还玩了冰上垂钓
And ice fishing.
颗粒无收
We did not get a bite.
最后我们发现  最好玩的是这个
In the end, the most fun thing to do is this.
推人玩儿吗
So... pushing?
冰上推人
Ice pushing.
说得对
It all makes sense!
你好  安迪  你好  奥利
Hi, Andy. Hi, Ollie.
您好  露易丝  吉恩和蒂娜的妈妈
Hi, Louise and Gene and Tina's mom!
今日推荐汉堡
"为时不晚"甜菜汉堡  5.95美元
露易丝交待要给您说
Louise said to say we're meeting
我们在地下室组建家庭作业小组
in the basement for homework club.
好的  玩的开心
Okay. Have fun.
家庭作业小组
Homework club?
天哪  他们不会要聚众嗑药吧
Oh, my God, they're doing drugs to each other!
用劲啊齐克  我都感觉不到你在推我
Push me till I feel something, Zeke!
好啊你们
Well, well, well.
老妈
Mom!
我们只是
we were just all getting...
来拿一颗  -什么
a-a head of... - Yeah?
一颗生菜
A head of lettuce.
妈  你还没往下看吧
Mom, you didn't happen to look down, did you?
事实上  我正要往下看  蒂娜
As a matter of fact, I'm looking down right now, Tina.
真是  太棒了
And... it's amazing!
天呐  还在闪闪发光
Oh, God, look at it shimmer!
这是冻住的水
It's frozen water!
人们把它叫做"冰"  它能改变世界
They call it "Ice," and it's gonna change the world!
如果你们要在这种冰面上推着玩儿
If you're gonna be pushing each other on the ice like this,
-就得有...  -头盔  我知道
- you need to be wearing... - Helmets. I know.
我都说无数次了
I've been a broken record about it.
不是  服装啊
No! Costumes!
带有亮片的那种闪瞎眼的服装
Glitzy ones with sequins!
我想当冰推界的坏小子
I want to be the bad boy of ice pushing
像埃尔维斯・斯托克那样
like Elvis Stojko!
加拿大花式滑冰运动员
我想当广播界的坏小子
And I want to be the bad boy of public radio,
像埃尔维斯・米切尔那样
like Elvis Mitchell!
美国影评人  广播主持人
我去拿服装
I'll go get the costumes.
别告诉你们老爸
and don't tell your father.
只要你保密
We won't if you won't!
我真是越来越喜欢那女人了
Got to love that woman.
嗨  琳
Hey, Lin.
-你  你这是要去哪  -啥
- Where-where... where are you going? - What?!
-什么  -没去哪
- What...? - What? Nowhere.
这是什么东西
What's this stuff?
-什么  -我们要做什么东西
- What? - What are we doing?
汉堡吗
We're making burgers?
开干吧  来
Let's do it. Let's go.
这是什么  要外带的吗
What's this? This is to-go?
喂  说你呐  接好
Hey, buddy, catch!
我  我来  天呐  琳
I-I got this. Geez, Lin.
给您
Here you go.
好啊  泰迪
Hey, there, Teddy.
请给我一个素食汉堡
One veggie burger, please.
借用一下洗手间  很快回来
I just got to use the restroom real quick.
你以前见过泰迪拿公文包吗
You ever see Teddy with a briefcase before?
就在那场话剧上见过一次
Only in that one play.
我都不记得了
I forgot about that.
把咖啡放下
Put the coffee down!
只有关键人物才有权喝咖啡
Coffee is for closers only!
泰迪  你在里面干嘛呢
Teddy, what are you doing in there?
洗洗手啊什么的
Washing my hands or something.
我能听出来你在吃东西
I can hear you chewing.
你在吃汉堡
You're chewing a burger.
你是不是让刚才那个人给你买了个汉堡
Did you get that guy to buy you a burger?!
才没有  我就是检查一下厕所
No, I'm just checking the bathroom
看有没有漏水
to see that it's not leaking.
-他还在吃  -泰迪  别吃了
- He's eating! - Teddy, stop eating.
你根本不知道我费了多大的劲
You don't know how hard this is for me.
我给了那个家伙三百刀托他帮我买这个汉堡
I paid that guy $300 to buy me this burger.
醒醒吧  泰迪  这都是你自找的
Come on, Teddy, you owe it to yourself.
-才不是  -好吧  那就算是为我
- No, I don't. Okay. - Well, then do it for me.
你帮我只是因为你觉得过意不去
You're just helping me because you feel guilty.
不是这样
That's not why.
就是  承认吧  鲍鲍
Yeah, it is. Admit it, Bobby.
-不  我没有  -别装了
- No, it's not. - Admit it!
泰迪  是因为  你是我的朋友
Teddy, it's because... you're my friend.
-你最要好的朋友  -我没说
- Your best friend! - I didn't say...
-最要好的  -琳达
- Besties. - Linda.
真的吗  鲍勃  我们是最好的朋友吗
Really, Bob? We're best friends?
我是说
I mean...
*直到地老天荒*
*Best friends*
-你们都是一对死党  -琳
- Till the very end! - Lin.
*丢掉工作时  他一头栽向你的沙发*
*He crashes on your couch when he loses his job*
*歹徒拔刀时  你勇敢地跳到他前面*
*A guy pulls a knife, and you jump in front*
-啥  -你一把夺过刀子
- What? - You take the blade
*捅进自己的肚子*
*Right in the gut!*
天呐
Oh, my God.
*他紧握你的双手  等救护车到来*
*Then he holds your hand till the medic comes...*
琳达  谢谢
Linda, thank you.
你这个混球  来抱一个  好哥们儿
You son of a bitch. Get in here, bestie.
好  你抱吧 抱吧
Okay. You got it. You got it.
*他磕破下巴时  你给他喂粥*
*You... feed him soup when he breaks his jaw*
*他长了那啥时  你帮他一尿畅通*
*You help him pee when he has that thing*
*他是你最要好的朋友*
*He's your best friend...*
曲棍球啊
Hockey.
差不多该睡觉了吧
Well, I-I guess it's time to hit the hay, huh?
-别别别  等一下  -怎么了
- Bup-bup-bup-bup, hold on, hold on. - What?
我接个电话  喂
I got to take this. Hello?
真的吗  我们通过了
Really? We got in?
太好了
How about that.
好的  早上见
Okay, hey, we'll see you in the morning.
大好消息
Tremendous news!
记不记得你说特技训练营超酷的
Remember how you said that stuntman boot camp was cool?
你  该不会给我们俩报名了吧
You... didn't sign us up for that, did you?
不仅如此  我还替我们俩报名参加
Better! I signed us up for the intensive weekend
周末的丛林强化训练了
boot camp retreat in the woods!
-啥  真的吗  -是的  整个周末
- What? You did? - Yup, the whole weekend.
这么说我可以一个人管理餐厅  冷藏库
So I'd watch the restaurant, the walk-in,
冷藏库里的所有东西  不用被你监督咯
everything in the walk-in, and you'd be gone?
没什么
Nothing.
住宿正好是两人间
And it's two to a cabin,
这下我们就是室友兼营友啦
so you and me will be roomie-caboomies!
我说不好  泰迪
I don't know, Teddy.
我感觉不大有兴趣
That, um, doesn't sound like something I want to do.
开玩笑  在丛林里玩特技是你的梦想好吗
What?! You've always wanted to do stunts in the woods.
没错  赶紧滚吧
Yeah. Get the hell out of here!
对  快去吧  老爸  走起来
Yeah, go for it, Dad. Do it!
虽然你已经玩过史上难度最高的特技
Though you've already pulled off the toughest stunt of all--
-那就是培养出三个优秀的小孩  -对
- raising three great kids. - Yeah.
走嘛  鲍鲍  我出钱
Come on, Bobby. My treat!
好吧  我去
Okay, I'll go.
你很...  谢谢
That's, um...Thanks.
没啥  不对  有啥
it's nothin'. Well, not nothin'.
之后三个月的电费我恐怕都交不起了
I won't have electricity for three months.
不过管它呢
But yay!
*丢掉工作时  他一头栽向你的沙发*
*He crashes on your couch when he loses his job*
-好吧  -你那啥时  他帮你一尿通畅
- Okay... - He helps you pee when you've got that thing
好吧  很好
Okay, that's great.
*他讨厌松鼠  就因你也讨厌*
*He hates squirrels 'cause you hate squirrels*
拜托别唱了
Please stop.
他是你最好的朋友
He's your best friend *
你最好的朋友
Your best friend...
这两天运动量应该会很大
There's gonna be a lot of exercise this weekend.
所以慢慢来  好吗
So take it easy, okay?
你现在不是状态最好的时候
You're not in the best shape, you know.
我懂  好兄弟
I know, best buddy.
好了  现在我要各位吐出压力
Okay. Now I need everybody to breath out stress...
呼入特技之气  特技之气
...breath in stunts. Stunts.
恭喜各位  你们体内现在已经有特技了
Congratulations, you've now got stunts inside of you.
现在我们要开始滚这个楼梯
Now we're gonna get cracking and roll down these stairs here.
你们会发现  摔下一整节楼梯
So everybody knows that falling down a flight of stairs
和坐100个仰卧起坐其实没啥区别
is the same as doing 100 sit-ups.
真的吗  我们真的要做这个
Really?We're doing this?
你是个半资深毒贩  现在正在楼梯间里
You're a mid-level drug dealer in an apartment stairwell.
摄像机开拍了
Cameras are rolling.
嘭  你被击中了
Bang! You've been shot.
开始  开始  快  动起来
Action! Action, man! Go! You got to go!
快  快  就是你了  鲍鲍
Go! This is a go. That's you, Bobby.
-该走了  -快快快
- That was a go. - Go, go, go go, go...!
啥  等等
What? Wait a...
太糟糕了
That was terrible!
你参加过公园的晨间格斗训练吗
Wait, have you done any of your morning melees in the park?
没有
No!
那你这样很容易受伤的
Well, then you could really get hurt.
欢迎来到冷冻竞技场
Welcome to the Freezer-Dome!
赢得这场的比赛的人可以把这宝贝带回家
Whoever wins this whole shebang takes this baby home!
好美
It's beautiful.
你们都好可爱哦
You all look so cute.
都绑好枕头了吗
Everyone got their pillows?
-安全措施都做好了吗  -好了
- Everyone safe? - Yes.
比赛开始
Now let's rumble!
屁股一着地  你就死了
If your butt touches ice, you're dead.
-真的吗  -不不  只是被淘汰宝贝
- Really? - No. No, you're just out, honey.
两人进场  一人出局
Two kids enter, one kid leaves!
第一组  鲁迪对战露易丝  开始
First up, Rudy versus Louise! Go!
我为什么要和鲁迪比
Why am I going against Rudy?
他一堆就倒  小菜一碟
He's a pushover, a cupcake.
什么  我很厉害的
What? I'm tough.
鲁迪  我和你一起上体育课的
Rudy, I'm in your P.E. Class.
踢球事件发生的时候我也在场
I was there for the kickball incident.
-那次很丢脸  -是的
- That was humbling. - Yeah.
是按体重级别来的  酷妞
Hey, it's called weight class, cool breeze.
接受现实吧  你也打不过大孩子
Deal with it. You can't hang with the big boys, anyway.
你说我打不过大孩子
Oh, I can't hang with the big boys?
我就要打给你看看
No, I'm gonna hang with the big boys.
等着瞧吧
You'll see.
看我信号  开始
Look at me. Ding!
得了  保重  兄弟
All right, take care, buddy.
下一个
Next!
真是妈妈的小乖乖
That's Mama's girl!
各位  这是糖做的玻璃
This is sugar glass, everyone.
打斗场面通常都以某人飞出窗户结束
Fights often end with someone flying through a window.
这是动作片里的惯用手法
It's a staple in action movies.
在有氧运动里也是
And an amazing cardio workout,
你们可以把它加到每天的常规训练里
which you can incorporate into your daily routine.
我奶奶就是这么做的
My grandmother does it.
泰迪  你正在找
Now, Teddy, you're looking for the guy
绑架你女儿的人
who kidnapped your daughter.
鲍勃  你就是那个绑架了他女儿的人
Bob, you're the guy who kidnapped his daughter.
你是个大坏蛋
You are a horrible person.
泰迪要找你报仇  开始吧
Teddy wants revenge. Go!
等下  为什么我是
Wait, why am I the person who's...
不
No!
我女儿在哪儿  混蛋
Where's my daughter, punk?!
放开  泰迪  放开我
Get... Teddy, get off.
放开我
Get off!
今天  你们中的一个将有幸
Today, one of you will advance
晋级冷冻竞技场的冠军赛
to the Freezer-Dome championship.
另外一人将抱憾离场
The other one will leave in shame.
但输的人也能拿到贴纸哦
But all the losers get stickers.
耻辱的贴纸
Stickers of shame!
开打吧
Now fight! Clank-clank!
你输定了  齐克
You're going down, Zeke.
我身体重心就比你低
Good luck with my low center of gravity.
我几乎是推不倒的
I'm practically unpushoverable.
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
来吧  小妞
Come on, girl!
我说过你输...
I told you you're going...
定了
...down.
我成功了  我把一个女孩推到了
Yeah! I did it! I pushed a girl
还不是因为我暗恋她但不知道如何表达
and not because I like her and didn't know how to show it!
抱歉了  亲爱的
Sorry, sweetie.
你得退场了  去吧  出去
You got to get off the ice. Go on, get off.
露易丝对战吉恩
Louise versus Gene!
轻松搞定她  吉恩
Easy win, Gene.
我在决赛等你
I'll be waiting for you in the finals.
如果他出现在决赛中  但长得却很像我
Well, if he shows up to the finals and looks like me,
那是因为那就是我  齐克
that's because it's me, Zeke!
你俩都是我的宝贝
I'm Mommy to both of you,
来看看谁想得到老妈更多的爱  开始
but let's see who wants Mommy's love more. Ding!
我可想得到老妈的爱了  接招
I want Mom's love pretty bad, so look out.
是么  吃我这招
Oh, yeah? How 'bout a little of this?
你比我想的要壮嘛
Well, you're sturdier than I thought.
又壮又萌
Sturdy and purdy.
等下  等下
Hold on, hold on.
我眼睛进东西了
I got something in my eye.
我去  真的进去了呢
Man, it's really in there.
吉恩  你先坐一下
Gene, have a seat.
我可能要一会儿
This could take a while.
- 没问题  -你上当了
- No problem. - You fell for it!
她光明正大地用诡计打败了你
She beat you fair and square,
就在这冰冻竞技场里
unfairly, here in the Freezer-Dome!
她将参加明天的冠军争夺赛
She advances to the finals tomorrow!
等着我  齐克
I'm coming for you, Zeke!
尽管来吧
Bring it on!
不是吧
You've got to be kidding me.
天呐  天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
起床了  特技男孩们
Wake up, stuntboys!
抱歉我没配喇叭
I'm sorry that was weird--
奇怪也凑合听吧
I don't have a bugle.
怎么就天亮了啊  不不不不
It can't be morning. No, no, no, no, no.
今天会很忙  你们将被机器人追赶
Big day today! You're gonna get chased by robots,
全身着火
get set on fire--
那会真的"烧"掉你们身上的卡路里
it literally burns the calories right off.
站住  人类
Freeze, human.
我们已经逮捕你了
We have apprehended you.
暂停  暂停  暂停
All right, time-out, time-out, time-out.
这怎么回事
What is going on here?
-天呐  -你都没有那种努力训练
- Oh, my God. - You don't have the mental fortitude of someone
让自己成为假特技演员的人的坚定信念
that wants to train to not be an actual stuntman.
我感觉你根本不想来这儿
It's like you don't even want to be here.
-因为我确实不想  -什么
-Because I don't! -What?!
听我说  我是因为内疚才来这儿
Look, guys, I only came here as a workout buddy
给我朋友泰迪作伴的
for my friend Teddy because I felt guilty.
他都算不上我朋友
I mean, he's not even my friend.
我听不懂你说什么
What are your words even meaning?
好吧  这事儿别跟别人说
Listen, between you and me,
我是为了让他保养身体  别老吃我家的
I had to say he was my best friend
汉堡  才说他是我最好朋友的
so he'd get healthy and not eat my burgers all the time.
对了  我是开汉堡店的
Oh, I sell burgers.
他确实是我最好的顾客
So he's really my best customer,
因为他成天就知道往嘴里塞汉堡
'cause all he does is shove burgers in his mouth.
但他不是我最好的朋友
But he's not my best friend.
我去  嗨  泰迪
Oh, my God. Hey, Teddy.
-嗨  -看来  你都听到了
- Hey. - So, uh, you just heard all that.
你还着火了
And you're on fire.
你说的那些话比被火烧还让人受伤
Those words hurt more than that fire.
他的身心都将伤痕累累
Yeah, he's gonna be scarred inside and outside.
我们该...
And o... We should put...
-帮他灭下火  灭火  -他受伤了
- put him out-- We should put him out. - He's scarring.
他要受伤了
He's starting to scar. Yeah.
你怎么可以骗我
How could you lie to me like that?!
既然我不是你最好的朋友你为啥要说是呢
Who says they're someone's best friend when they're not?!
我骗你是因为我在乎你
I lied because I care about you.
靠边  就这儿  停车  鲍勃
Pull over here. Here! Stop the car, Bob!
又不是只有你家卖汉堡
You're not the only guy that serves burgers.
现在我要做达斯狄餐厅的常客了  朋友
I'm gonna be a regular at Dusty's Feedbag now, friend.
别这样  泰迪  别...
Come on, Teddy, d...
还有  三年前
And one more thing-- three years ago,
你忘了给我的汉堡加番茄  我啥也没说
you forgot a tomato on my burger and I said nothing--
啥也没说
nothing!
泰迪  别进去
Teddy, don't go in there!
用不着你来指挥我
You don't tell me what to do!
慢着  这个门好像没开
Oh, wait, I guess this entrance isn't open.
是从后面进的
It's around the back.
那就回来吧
Then just come back here.
你  开你的车吧
You... Keep driving!
是在旁边么  还是
Is it around the side or...
我这是在哪儿啊
Where am I? Something.
就在正前方  那么大扇门
It's right there in the front, the huge entrance.
快走  鲍勃
Get out of here, Bob!
我不需要你帮忙
I don't need your help!
男孩女孩们  女孩男孩们
Boys and girls, girls and boys,
美利坚未来的成年人们
future adults of America,
是时候进行这世上最重要的事了
it's time for the most important thing in the world...
冰冻竞技场冠军争夺赛
the Freezer-Dome finals!
你们中只有一人能把它带回家
Only one of you will go home with this!
我要定那腰带了
I want that belt.
我可不会被你的小把戏骗到  小妞
And I'm not gonna fall for your little tricks, girl.
我也不会设计陷害你  齐克
I wouldn't try to trick you, Zeke.
开始
Ding!
等等  等等
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
我眼睛进东西了
I got something in my eye.
等一下  等一下
Hold on, hold on.
好吧  那我坐着休息一下
All right, I guess I'll just take a seat here,
先蹲下来...
bend my little knees down...
才怪
Just kidding!
我就知道你会来这招
Hey, hey, you had to try.
知道为什么吗  因为你弱爆了
You know why? 'Cause you're tiny!
你回家早了啊
You're home early.
是训练强度太大了吗
What, did you pull a hammy?
不是  一言难尽  琳达呢
No. Long story. Where's Linda?
在楼下  我猜
Downstairs, I think.
麦克  你在干嘛
Mike, what are you doing?
好奇怪  通常我都是在那边的
That's weird. I'm normally over there.
我还以为你和泰迪在一起呢
I thought you were with Teddy.
他去达斯狄餐厅了
He's at Dusty's Feedbag,
那是他现在最爱的餐厅
his new favorite restaurant.
-那可不太妙  -为什么
- Oh, that's not good. - Why?
你没听过"挤爆裤腰带汉堡"么
You haven't heard of the Belt Buckle Belly Buster?
那餐厅就有这个
They serve that there.
"挤爆裤腰带汉堡"
Belt Buckle Belly Buster?
是一个五磅重的汉堡
It's a five-pound burger.
如果能在半小时内吃完
If you eat the whole thing in a half hour,
就能免单  你的照片也会被贴在墙上
it's free, and you get your picture on the wall.
不不不不不  泰迪
Oh, no, no. No, no, no, no. Teddy!
所以我可以继续吃免费冰淇淋咯
So you said it's cool to have more ice cream?
你会输得一败涂地的
You're gonna get destroyed.
-投降吧  -不可能
- Throw in the towel! - Never.
不可能  不可能  不可能
Never, never, never!
快灭了她
Finish her!
为啥还要挣扎呢  柔弱小天使
Why you putting up a fight, you tiny sweet angel?
准备好接受惩罚吧  小妞  认输吧
Take your medicine, girl. Just go down.
我  我一定会赢的
I'm s... I'm still totally gonna win,
所以闭上你的嘴吧
so shut your mouth.
露易丝  虽然你打败了我
You might have beaten me, Louise,
但血浓于冰  好吧并没有
but blood is thicker than ice. But not actually.
是时候放野兽出笼了
Time to unleash the beast.
我去
Oh, God.
机会来了
Now's your chance!
那玩意儿简直能让恐龙灭绝
Oh, that's what killed the dinosaurs.
太可怕了
That's awful.
齐克倒下了  露易丝  你赢了
Zeke is down! Louise, you win!
全都来膜拜我吧
Everybody kiss my butt
-全都来膜拜我  -膜拜她
- Everybody kiss my butt - Kiss her butt
-全都来膜拜我  -全都去膜拜她
- Everybody kiss my butt - Everybody kiss her butt
-泰迪  -鲍勃
- Teddy! - Bob.
你没点"挤爆裤腰带汉堡"吧
You didn't order the Belt Buckle Belly Buster, did you?
点了又怎样  没点又怎样
Maybe I did, maybe I didn't.
-我点了  -不好意思
- But I did. - Excuse me.
你是达斯狄吗
Are you Dusty?
达斯狄
Dusty?
不是  这儿没有达斯狄
No. There's no Dusty.
我们这是连锁店  朋友
This is a chain, pal.
我叫凯文  是这里的经理
I'm Kevin. I'm the manager.
凯文  你不能卖给这人那五磅重的汉堡
Listen, Kevin, you can't serve this guy your five-pound burger.
好的  我记一下
Oh, okay, making a note.
我不能在自己的餐厅里卖汉堡
I can't serve someone a burger in my own restaurant.
听我说  泰迪他...
Look, Teddy is... Well...
他有一颗超级臃肿的心脏
He has the biggest heart of anyone I know.
既因为他心胸特别宽广
Both because he's incredibly sweet
也因为那里面全是胆固醇
but also because it's full of cholesterol.
所以你不能卖给他那个超级汉堡
Which is why you can't serve him that huge burger--
那  那会害死他的
he-he might not survive it.
知道吗  这兄弟可付钱了
Well, you know what? Big boy paid for it,
上汉堡
so order up!
我的天呐  看看这玩意儿
Good God, look at that thing.
-我开动了  -我不准你卖这汉堡给他
- Let me at it! - You're not giving him that burger.
别这样  放开那"挤爆裤腰带汉堡"
Come on, let that Belly Buster through.
小姐  拜托把这汉堡端回厨房
Please take the burger back to the kitchen, ma'am.
真奇怪  你以为自己是这里的谁啊
It is so weird that you think you work here. I just...
该死  我怎么不记得
Damn it, I don't remember
雇过一个肥胖版的毕雷诺斯了
hiring a fat Burt Reynolds.
美国男演员
这汉堡哪儿也别想去
Look, this burger is not going anywhere.
真是太棒了
This is just fantastic.
我要把超重版毕雷诺斯扔出我的餐厅了
I'm gonna get to throw fat Burt Reynolds out of my restaurant!
是么  我也不是好惹的
Oh, yeah? Well, I can get tough, too.
我可不会走
And I'm staying.
二位  别这样  别为了我打架
Guys, come on. Don't fight over me.
等等  这是真的吗
Wait, is that what's happening?
告诉你个坏消息  凯文
Bad news for you, Kevin.
我刚接受过一些很牛逼的训练
I've just been through a bunch of kick-ass training,
你要是以为你能...  别
so if you think you can just... Oh, no...
是么  但愿你训练过如何挨揍
Oh, yeah? Well, I hope you got trained to get your ass kicked!
我真的训练过  天呐
Actually, I did! Oh, God!
撞玻璃场面来了
Here comes the glass!
感谢惠顾
Thanks for coming!
你还好吗  鲍鲍
Are you okay, Bobby?
真玻璃撞上去好痛
Real glass hurts so bad.
我流血了吗
Am I bleeding?
没  没流太多
Not, like, too much.
地上还没摆气垫
And the concrete wasn't padded.
我落地的时候撞得好厉害
It was so hard when-when I landed on it.
在你昏迷前我一定要说
Before you pass out,
这是别人为我做过的最棒的事
that's the nicest thing anyone's ever done for me.
我身上有好多玻璃渣
I have so much glass in myself.
我带你离开这儿  鲍鲍
I'll get you out of here, buddy.
我们去医院吧  泰迪
All right, let's go to the hospital, Teddy.
不  鲍勃  我们回家
No, Bob. Let's go home.
不  不  我们要去医院
No. No, we're gonna go to a hospital...
我说回家就回家  鲍勃
Home it is, Bob.
下车了  再几步就到家了
Here we go, almost home.
让其它人来扶我好了
I'll just see if someone else can take me.
听着  就算我不是你最好的朋友
Hey, even though I'm not your best friend,
我还是很感激你为我做的一切
I really appreciate what you did.
抱歉我说你不是我最好的朋友了
Look, I-I'm sorry I said you're not my best friend.
-你是的  -是么
- Because you are. - I am?
是的  这取决于你怎么定义好朋友
Yeah, I mean, it depends on how you define it.
技术层面来说  你确实是我最好的朋友
You technically are my best friend.
不过  我也可能...
But, I mean... I might meet...
不用说了  鲍鲍
Bup, bup, bup-- stop right there, Bobby.
但我想说  我不确定...
But, I mean, I don't know who...
鲍勃  鲍勃  鲍勃
Yeah. Bob, Bob, Bob, Bob.
-我最终...  -够了
- Eventually I... - Enough.
可以让我抱着你跨过门槛吗
Can I carry you across the threshold?
好吧
All right.
注意头  抱歉
Watch your head. Sorry.
我可怜的被人海扁一顿的鲍鲍
My little beat-up Bobby.
那腰带哪儿来的
Where's that belt from?
我们的存货都去哪儿了
Where's all the food?
冰地有用吗
Is the ice helping?
-很提神吧  -是的  蒂娜
- Pretty refreshing, right? - Yes, Tina.
这个呢  这有用吗
How 'bout this? Is this helping?
谢了  泰迪  嗯  很舒服
Thanks, Teddy. Yes, it's good.
-再来点嗅盐怎么样  -我天  拜托
- How 'bout some smelling salts? - Oh, God. Come on!
嗅盐  可用作苏醒剂
我才拜托你咧
Oh, you come on.
那瓶屁可是制胜法宝  你知道的
That fart's a winner and you know it!
好吧  让我再闻一次
All right, let me smell it again.
是啊  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
*他丢掉工作的时候  一头栽向你的沙发*
*He crashes on your couch when he loses his job*
*歹徒拔刀时  你勇敢地跳到他前面*
*Guy pulls a knife and you jump in front*
*你一把夺过刀子  捅进自己的肚子*
*You take the blade right in the gut *
*他紧握你的双手  等救护车到来*
*Then he holds your hand till the medic comes *
*他磕破下巴时  你给他喂粥*
*You feed him soup when he breaks his jaw *
*他长了那啥时  你帮他一尿畅通*
*You help him pee when he has that thing *
*他是你最要好的朋友*
*He's your best friend! *
*丢掉工作时  他一头栽向你的沙发*
*He crashes on your couch when he loses his job *
*他长了那啥时  你帮他一尿畅通*
*He helps you pee when you've got that thing *
*他是你最要好的朋友*
*He's your best friend *
*最要好的朋友*
*Your best friend! *